Hello, this video will be a walkthrough of how you can do Task 1 using reagent.
So you'll go click on Task 1. This is just that index HTML file in the starter code.
And you'll get this kind of email composition style interface.
There's this big text area for the body and also a spot where you can put the subject of your email.
I'm going to grab an example email from
the starter code. This is that test-email-1.txt, and I'll just paste that into the body. And the
idea of this application is that we should be able to press the suggest button and instead of
nothing happening, which is what just happened, it should populate the subject line with a
kind of reasonable subject
for the body of the email.
So to do that, we're going to add some AI magic.
We'll do that using reagent, which is linked in your homework.
First, log in.
You'll need to log in with GitHub
and make sure this is the same GitHub account
that you've told course staff about in the past.
You'll want to go to the Organizations tab,
and you'll see that you have an invitation from your class.
If you don't, you need to contact your course staff and get that figured out.
Click on the check mark, and then go to Noggins.
Now, a Noggin is a custom AI tool within this software reagent that will create an API that you can use within your application.
I'll show you what that means.
First, we'll go to “New Noggin”.
And I'll just type Task 1, because that's the task we're doing.
And you'll want to create a Noggin owned by your class organization.
Now, you'll notice when we do that,
we have a limit to how much we're allowed to spend in this organization
based on the amount of money that we've been kind of allotted to the,
in the organization.
So I'm going to budget just five credits.
That's five US cents for this task.
We're not going to need any more than that.
And then I'll choose an AI model.
Which models show up will depend on how your organization is configured,
but I'm going to use this GPT-4o-mini model,
which is a pretty cheap model that is more than good enough for this task.
I'll hit create.
And there's a lot going on on this page. Most of it you don't
have to worry about right now. The model parameters you might want to play around with a bit. Later
we'll look at how you can play with the model output as well. But the most important thing
is going to be this chat prompt section. The system prompt is for more general
instructions, like “Make sure to respond in English”, or things like that.
But here we'll use the chat prompt to tell the model what to do. This is a lot like ChatGPT.
If I just say, “Tell me a joke”, this is actually using the same LLM that powers ChatGPT.
I go to the Use tab up herem, and click Run, and hey, it tells us a joke.
That's... I don't know, that's a decent joke. LLMs aren't great at telling jokes, but this one's a
classic. Now, if I go back into the chat prompt, I can say, I don't know, “Tell me a knock knock joke”.
And if I try this, you'll see that that prompt is updated and, eh,
I don't know, that's a decent joke too. Now, one thing we can do in a chat prompt is actually
add multiple chat turns in the prompt. Let me show you what that means. Let me grab that
knock, knock joke we just got. And what I want to kind of tell the LLM is that I don't care about this,
sure, here you go. And I also want the joke in a particular format. So I'm going to go here
and just click on “Switch the chat speaker”. You can also press Shift-Enter and paste in that
response. Now, say I want it to have this kind of A, B,
A, B, kind of a format.
I'll press Shift-Enter.
Now tell me another one.
What this will do is going to show the model,
hey, here's what it looked like last time you responded to this prompt.
So maybe the model is more likely to respond that way the next time. If I click run, that's what we see, right? The same format,
and another classic joke. Now, reagent doesn't just let us talk to the LLM directly, it also
lets us create a prompt template that we can then use as an API.
This one should be about, I'm going to add a template variable.
You can click on this button here or just type a dollar sign, topic.
I hit enter there and I'll just add a period.
Now if I go to the use tab, you'll see we have this
field that we can fill out. I'll say baseball. Uh, it's not a great joke, right? But as you can see,
we were able to kind of fill in the prompt. Uh, if I wanted a joke about uh,
computer science. I could type that in and that would fill in the prompt there as well.
Wait, yeah, these, like I said, LLMs, not actually great at jokes.
Let's go on to something that LLMs are good at.
The task at hand.
So we talked about how we can see this, what we want is to create a subject for this email based on the body, so that when we click on suggest, we'll see it show up right here.
I've written this email. Please suggest a reasonable subject line for it.
And I'll create a variable.
I'm going to bump up the maximum length just a little.
This is in characters, just because 500 is a little short.
And then I'm going to grab this email, and let's see how it does.
I'll hit run.
Yeah, that's about right.
That's a good subject line for the email I just pasted in.
Now, when we use this in our application,
I'm not going to want it to put “Subject:” inside the field.
So I'm going to ask it not to do that.
Please make sure not to include any prefix like subject. Just include the subject line you're predicting.
And now when I try, yeah, looks like that fixed the problem.
So what's interesting about reagent is that if we go to this use tab, this actually creates
an API that we can call directly.
If I go grab this URL and paste it in up here, I can say, hey, do you want to get lunch? And we'll get that subject line right here in the response from the API.
Now, you'll notice that there's an API key kind of built into this API. This is what
authenticates the request so that you're actually allowed to use the API. It's generally
not a great idea to just throw an API key right into your own code,
but as the reagent UI points out here, it's not a huge deal to, like if this API key got leaked,
the only thing you'd be able to do with it is generate an email subject line, which is what we
wanted to happen anyway. But just keep in mind that normally you do want to be a little more careful with how you use these API keys.
So I'm going to go back into the code for Task 1.
And first, let's just get used to how we can actually modify the page.
I'll scroll down to where it says, your code here.
Now already we've included this event listener.
When the button gets clicked, that button that says, you know,
suggest me a subject line, we will put the value of that main text area,
the body of the email, into a variable.
So I can, for example, console.log, email, body,
and I'll just save that.
And if I open up my console,
what I'll find when I refresh,
and here, let me just go grab that email again,
paste it in, right?
We have that information right here.
Now, I can also use this line of code,
setting dot value equal to a string, test subject,
and now when I refresh and click, that works too.
So now we're going to go get that API that we just created within reagent,
and we'll use it in our code. If I go back to the Noggin and go over to this JavaScript section,
reagent gives us a little bit of JavaScript code. We can copy that. It's okay if you don't
know exactly how this code works. Get rid of that line. The most important part of this little snippet
reagent gave us is where it says fill variables here. This is where we'll be
able to fill in that email variable that we created in our prompt. So I'm
going to fill it with the value of this email body variable.
I just type email body and now after the Noggin has been used the response variable will contain the response from the Noggin.
So we'll just go ahead and console.log response just so that we see that happen.
Now if I refresh I'll go ahead and grab this email again.
And when I click Suggest, it takes a second, but we get this subject back.
Now, if you go into reagent, you're actually able to see that subject,
that API call being made right here.
So I'll do it with another email just to prove that.
If I click on suggest again, we get another response and here we can see this call that we
actually made from within our code shows up right here in reagent. So keep that in
mind. It can be useful if you're noticing you're having some trouble, it's not behaving how you expect. This is a way that you can see exactly
what is being sent to the model and exactly what the model responded. Now finally, we can just
take that response and put it into here. And that should be everything. Let me grab another
email, just paste that into the body. Let me grab another email.
Just paste that into the body.
And when I click suggest immediately, well, not immediately, but pretty quickly, it suggests
a subject line for this body of this email.
And we can try other things.
This one's in Spanish.
It's talking about a job interview. And yeah, look, it's talking about a job interview.
And yeah, look, it's talking about a job interview. You'll find that it's not super consistent whether it responds in English or Spanish.
In fact, if you run it more than once, it looks like we got the same result,
but sometimes you'll actually be able to get it to respond in different ways.
If you want a little more variety, you can drag up this temperature variable,
or if you want it to be totally consistent, drag it all the way down to zero.
Now if I refresh, we'll see, I have not been spending a lot of money on this. This particular
API is pretty cheap. This is 0.03 US cents that we have spent on all of the requests we've
made so far. So you can even dial this budget down just by clicking on that pencil.
If later in the homework you realize you're using more money than you are expecting,
you can probably take some of the budget away from this to free up some budget for
other noggins.
A couple other things to mention is that if you want to create an image variable, you can do it by just changing the type of the variable over here.
And maybe set in image quality. Low is normally good enough.
And then you'll be able to upload images into the prompt, and you'll see later in the homework how you can do that in your code as well.
And also, if you want to change the output structure, here let me change this back to a text
variable, you can switch in some models, not all of them support this, from freeform text to structured
data. And reagent has this interface that lets you say, I don't know, we'll do subject, freeform text.
This isn't a great example, but you will see one later in your homework.
And now, if I paste an email into this, what we'll see is we actually get this kind of JSON object
that contains the format that you saw there. So later in the homework when you need to do that,
that's how you'll do it. But that's all. You have successfully implemented Task 1, and I hope you
enjoy the rest of them.